so today's the second lecture about
所以今天是关于第二讲
network programming we got started last
网络编程中，我们开始了最后
time and as you probably saw last time
时间，因为你 可能看到的最后一次
there the AP is for this are really big
那里的AP是这个是真正的大
and hairy and messy and it takes just a
多毛和杂乱，它需要只是一个
lot of time in my own personal
很多时间在我自己的个人
experience of rereading we looking at
重读我们在看的经验
code looks good examples rereading
代码看起来很好的例子重读
documentation going back and forth over
文档来回过
that a dozen or so times before it all
在此 之前，这一切 十几倍
really sinks in and it's one where it
真汇在和它的一个地方
really helps a lot to look at example
真的有很多益处看例子
code and there's example code in the
代码和有示例代码中
book in that CSAP pc file that you've
在书中，你已经 是 CSAP PC文件
seen versions of in various forms so I
在各种形式的看到的版本 ，所以 我
can lecture for days and weeks but it's
可以训斥几天和几周，但它
really what we'd all settle in until
难道就是我们想要的所有定居，直到
you've spent time studying yourself
你花时间自己学习
anyways I want to repeat and go back
反正我想重复 并返回
over a little bit of ground before but
在之前的地面 一点点 ，但
last time we talked about the idea of
上次我们谈到 的想法
translating from a domain name which is
从作为域名翻译
something like w w CMU edu to IP address
类似WW CMU EDU 到IP地址
which for IP version 4 is a is a 32-bit
这对于IP 版本4是是一个32位的
address it's usually written in dotted
地址它通常用虚线
decimal form and I showed you a program
十进制的形式和 我向您展示一个程序
last time called host info that you
所谓的主机信息最后一次，你
could that will look actually at the
可以将 实际看
code for
代码
and I just wanted to show you today I
我只是想今天告诉你我
just did one very small tweak to that
只是做了一个非常小的调整到
program and I'll describe it today and
计划今天我将描述它，
the interesting thing is it lets you
有趣的是 ， 它可以让你
look at both ipv4 and ipv6 and it's one
看IPv4和IPv6，它是一个
of the interesting features the code in
有趣的功能代码
the book and it's new to the third
这本书，这是新来的第三
edition is it uses a new API that lets
版是它采用了全新的API， 让
you pretty easily
你很容易地
write code that will work under either
编写的代码 将在工作，要么
of these two versions of the Internet
互联网这两个版本的
Protocol so for example with this
协议， 例如 用此
slightly modified program if I now look
稍微修改程序 ，如果我现在看
up the IP address for Facebook you'll
了IP 地址为 Facebook 您会
see it comes back with two different
看到它与两个不同的回来
ones and the the first one is the
那些与第 一个是
familiar dotted decimal form where each
熟悉点分十进制形式，其中每
read call that each of these digits it's
读取调用每个这些数字 是
a decimal representation of a single
单个的十进制表示
byte so it's a number between 0 and 255
字节所以它是0 和255 之间的数字
this is a ipv6 address which is I told
这是一个IPv6地址这是我跟
you is 128 bits long so that to the
你是128位长，这样的
seventh takeaway 3 to the fifth 32 bytes
第七外卖 3到第五32个字节
right and it's usually written in the
右它通常写在
text format
文本格式
with colons after every pair of bytes
与每对的字节之后冒号
and I think the colon colon just means
我认为结肠结肠只是意味着
that's a 0 there when the cute things
这是一个 0那里的可爱的东西时，
Facebook did was embed fa c e is a hex
Facebook上也被嵌入 前言 e 是一个十六进制
code inside observe ipv6 address
代码中看到IPv6地址
and actually just I get very different
而实际上只是我得到很大的不同
results running this at home and than I
结果运行这个家比我
do here and as I mentioned you'll get
在这里做和我 提到你会得到
different results running a DNS server
运行DNS服务器不同的结果
depending where in the country are out
根据 其中在 全国 是 出
if you repeat the same thing over and
如果你重复同样的事情，并
over again you'll get different results
一遍又一遍，你会得到不同的结果
and that's because these very large
那是因为这些非常大
companies are providing servers that are
公司提供 的 服务器
stationed all over the world and it's a
驻扎在世界各地 ，这是一个
way to sort of balance out the load of
办法之类的平衡 出的负载
the traffic they also have multiple
交通也有多个
server addresses that then they kind of
服务器解决了，然后他们那种
rotate through to give you so that
轮换给你，让
different people will get served by
不同的人 会得到服务
different machines so you see for
不同的机器，所以你看到的
example Twitter our Google just gave me
例如Twitter的谷歌我们只是给了我
two addresses in ipv4 and ipv6 address
在IPv4 和IPv6地址的 两个地址
Twitter gave me a for different ipv4
微博给了我一个针对不同的IPv4
addresses so let's look then at the code
地址，以便让我们再来看一下代码
I'll go back through some of what we
我会通过一些 什么 回去 我们
talked about last time I quite honestly
谈到最后一次， 我坦白地说
I spent a fair amount of time looking at
我花了很多时间相当看着
it so I can really understand it better
它 让我能真正 更好地 了解它
because it's pretty it's not simple
因为它是相当它不是简单
stuff but as I mentioned the as we went
的东西，但正如我 所说 的 ，我们去了
over last time this is sort of this
比去年 这个 时间 是有点这个
giant block diagram that shows all the
巨框图，显示所有的
activity involved in setting up and
活动参与建立和
running both a server and a client and
同时运行在服务器和客户端和
just to repeat the idea is you need to
只是重复的想法是，你需要
the server needs to fire up you can't
服务器需要火起来你不能
contact its server until that server
联系它的服务器，直到 该服务器
exists so it's the server is the thing
存在所以它的服务器是 事
that has to exist first and all these
有存在 第一和所有这些
steps are what are required for a server
是都需要一个服务器的步骤是什么
to begin on a machine and then to accept
开始一台机器上，然后接受
a connection request from a client
来自客户机的连接请求
similarly once the server is set then
同样，一旦服务器设置，那么
the client can begin and it's like
客户端可以开始，它就像
placing a call to the server and it
发出呼叫服务器 ，它
makes a connection request and that's
使一个连接 请求，这就是
accepted by the server and then what's
服务器接受，然后什么
called a session begins meaning an
称为会话开始的意思
ability for these two machines to talk
能力这两款机器说话
back and
回
fourth over an internet connection and
第四 通过因特网连接 和
they'll do it this example I'll show is
他们会做这个例子中，我会展示的是
done by reading and writing as if they
通过阅读和写作做，就好像它们
were filed a file each end looks like
共立案文件中的每个底好像
it's reading and writing a file and then
它的读取和写入一个文件，然后
once the client is done with whatever it
一旦客户用 什么 做 它
it's trying to get it will disconnect
它试图让它将断开连接
since we hang up its phone and then the
因为我们挂了其电话，然后
listening the server will detect this by
监听服务器将通过检测该
receiving an into file when it attempts
接收到文件时， 它试图 时
to read from the client and then it will
从客户端读取，然后它会
close that connection but and this I
关闭连接，但这个 我
didn't have stated quite properly last
没得相当正确最后陈述
time this it's not going to actually
这个时间，它不会实际
shut down at that point it's just going
关闭在这一点上 它只是要
to return back and accept a new
即可返回 ，并接受新
connection request and this is what's
连接请求，这是什么
known as an iterative server it can only
被称为 一个迭代服务器时，它只能
handle a single client at a time later
同时处理一个客户端 后
in the course we'll talk about how to do
在使用过程中，我们将讨论如何做
a multi-threaded server that can handle
一个多线程的服务器，它可以处理
multiple connections at one time this is
在同一时间，这是多个连接
a pretty basic version so the first step
一个非常基本的版本，所以第一步
on either the client or the server side
在客户端或 服务器端上
is this very hairy messy relatively new
这是非常毛茸茸凌乱相对较新
API called get adder info and the idea
API名为get 加法信息和想法
of get adder info is it's a sort of
的加法器获得的信息是它的几分
kitchen sink our Swiss Army knife if you
厨房水槽 我们的瑞士军刀，如果你
know all those expressions of it has a
知道所有这些表达式的它有一个
zillion features that sort of subsume a
数不胜数的功能排序的那一个归入
lot of other sort of individual
很多其他种类的个人
protocols so for example it's pretty
协议因此，例如，它很
much the same whether it's ipv4 ipv6 it
大同小异无论 是IPv4的IPv6的 它
lets you sort of go forward from and a
您拍下的往前走，从和
domain name to an IP address but to go
域名到IP 地址 ，但去
backward from an IP address back to a
从IP地址返回给落后
domain name it supports all of those
域名它支持所有的
things it will let you look up what is
东西它会让你抬头是什么
the port number associated with an HTTP
与HTTP相关联的端口号
server so we'll let you do all kinds of
服务器， 所以 我们会让你做 各种
different things and as a result it's a
不同的东西 ，因此它是一个
big and messy API with a zillion
有 无数大而凌乱API
zillions features and parameters and so
不计其数的功能和参数等
forth so you recall from last time that
第四让你从上次记得
the the data structures we use to refer
我们使用的数据结构是指
to a connection whether it's an ipv4 or
到连接它是否是IPv4或
an ipv6 connection is called a sock
IPv6连接被称为袜子
adder and as I mentioned this is sort of
加法器和我提到这是有点
the C version of subtyping if you know a
子类型的 C版，如果你知道
language with a type inheritance
语言具有类型继承
this is how it's done in C it's done by
这是它是如何用C实现它是由做
casting and so in particular the sort of
尤其是那种铸造等
generic socket address all it needs to
通用套接字 地址的所有它需要
know is a two byte field at the front
知道是两个 字节字段在前面
that specifies what kind of socket is
指定什么 样的插座是
this and then in particular we'll be
这一点，然后我们尤其会
looking at what's called a sock adder in
在看什么 叫做袜子加法器
which is an ipv4 version of of a socket
这是一个插座的 IPv4 版
and so what it needs to know is a port
所以它需要知道什么 是端口
number which is a two byte integer and a
这是一个两个字节的整数和一个数
I P address which is a four byte address
IP地址是一个四个字节地址
for ipv4 both of those are actually
对于IPv4 这两个其实都是
stored in this structure as I mentioned
存储在此结构正如我所提到
in in big-endian order even if you're
在大端顺序，即使你
running it on a little endian machine
运行它小 端机器 上
and one of the interesting features of
和有趣的 功能之一
that this API this get adder info is
这个 API 这个 加法器获取的信息是
it's largely removed the need for you as
它主要是删除， 因为需要你
a programmer to worry about byte
程序员担心字节
ordering and that's a nice feature so in
订货，这是一个很好的功能， 所以在
general for example and get adder info
一般的例子 ，得到 加法信息
if I want to pass an ax port number I'll
如果我想传递一个斧子的端口号我会
pass it as a character string a string
把它作为一个字符串的 字符串
representation of a decimal number in
在一个十进制数表示
other words and then the code here
换句话说，然后这里的代码
within this API will automatically turn
在这个API将自动关闭
that into a 16-bit integer and put it in
即到一个16位整数，并把它放在
the proper byte order and same with how
正确的字节顺序，同着如何
it takes use of this 32 bit IP address
它需要使用该32位的IP地址
and you want to get it into dotted
并且要让它进入点
decimal form it will do that for you
小数形式，它会为你做的
without you having to worry about byte
没有你 不必担心字节
order so it's kind of a nice thing
为了使这类型的好处
so get editor info has a whole bunch of
所以得到编辑的信息有 一大堆
arguments and some of them are
参数和它们中的一些
essentially outputs some of them are
本质上输出 它们中的一些
inputs things you're passing into the
你传递到输入的东西
function another it's really more like
另一个功能 它看起来更像
outputs how it gets information back to
输出如何获取 信息回
you
您
so in particular the first one is just
所以特别是第一个就是
the name of the host and that can be
主机的名称 和可
either a domain name or a dotted decimal
无论是域名或点分十进制
name or one of those funky looking
命名或那些时髦的一个期待
things with the colons that you solve
事情是你解决冒号
for ipv6 the service is usually if
IPv6的服务 通常是，如果
you're looking up so if we're using this
你正在寻找，这样即使我们使用这个
to look up that'll actually be a null
查找该会实际上 是一个空
pointer and basically what typically
指针和基本上是典型的
you'll have is one of those two will be
你必须在 这两个 之一 将是
a string and the other will be a null
一个字符串，而另一个将是 一个空
pointer and the reason for that is the
指针和其中的原因是
same function can be used either to look
同样的功能既可以用来查找
up a service like what is the port
像什么端口服务
number associated with HTTP or it can be
与HTTP相关号，或者它可以是
what is the IP address of WWC mu edu the
什么是WWC 亩 的 IP 地址 的埃杜
hints is something that you're passing
提示的是，你传递的东西
in and it's basically is you fill in a
在和它基本上 是你在填写
small amount of a fairly large body of
一个相当大的体量小
information about what specifically are
什么具体的信息
you looking for in this request are you
你 在这个要求 找 你
looking for an ipv6 information are you
寻找一个IPv6的信息是你
looking for ipv4 and so forth and then
寻找IPv4 和等等，然后
what it returns back that's why you pass
它返回这就是为什么你传递
a star star is it will return back a
明星星后会返回一个
linked list that it's generated of
， 它的生成链接列表
results and the reason for that as I
结果其中的原因 ，因为我
mentioned is that IP addresses are sort
提到的是，IP地址排序
of many to many mapping potentially
的多对多映射潜在
there as you saw it's possible for a
还有当你看到它是可能的
single domain name to have multiple IP
单个域名有多个IP
addresses it's possible for a single IP
地址有可能 为一个单一的 IP
address to have multiple domain names
针对有多个域名
and so this is how they handle that sort
所以这是他们如何处理排序
of fact that they return a whole list of
事实上， 他们返回的整个列表
results and associated with that once
结果，并 与 相关的 一次
that result gets you
这个结果让你
once you're done with it you're supposed
一旦你用它做你 应该
to call a function called free adder
呼叫被叫 免费加法器功能
info that will basically dispose of all
信息将基本配置所有的
the elements of that linked list you
那 你 链接列表 的元素
don't have to do it yourself with free
不必自己与做免费的
and then there's a another helper
然后有一个又一个帮手
function called gar ster error that you
函数调用的雀鳝STER错误 ，你
use if there's an error code to help you
使用，如果有一个错误代码，以帮助您
interpret that
这解释
err and it returns an error code so as I
犯错 并返回 一个 错误代码，以便为我
mentioned it returns up a linked list
提到它返回一个链表
that result is a linked list of these
这一结果是这些链表
get of adders structs edit info structs
得到加法器的结构编辑信息 结构
and the adder info struct has iliyan
而加法器信息结构有iliyan
field some of which you'll use and some
外地 其中 一些 你会使用一些
which you won't this is for example when
你会不会这是例如当
you're passing in hints hints is sort of
你传递的提示线索有几分
that what you're passing in the
您传递什么样的
information you know some conditions
信息你知道一些条件
about what you're looking for in this
关于你在这找什么
request and then what some of these you
请求，然后某些资料 你
pass in and some of it returns and so
通过在和它的一些返回 等
some of these fields are ones that then
一些领域 是那些然后
you can use when you're making calls to
您可以在正在对呼叫使用
other socket functions functions in the
在其他socket函数功能
socket library it'll fill in instead of
套接字库，它会填补，而不是
you having to worry about what's the
你不必担心 有什么
structure the format of a sock adder in
结构袜子 加法器 的格式
and how do I convert into network order
和我怎么转换成网络秩序
and stuff it will do all that for you
和东西会尽 一切 为你
so it's a little confusing to use though
所以这是一个有点混乱，虽然使用
because sometimes the stuff you're
因为有时候东西 你
providing is stuff you're giving it and
提供的东西，你给它，
sometimes it's stuff that it's returning
有时它的东西， 它的返回
back to you and then there's an inverse
回到你，然后 有一个逆
function that so get editor info is
函数，所以得到编辑的信息是
given a it's actually give me the
给予它实际上给我
address information about some name and
解决的一些名称信息和
get name info is I give you an address
获得名称的信息是我给你一个地址
and you give me back some documentation
你给 我带回 一些文档
about it including potentially a domain
关于它 可能 包括 一个域
name so there you pass in as a the first
名称，以便您有在传递的第一
argument is a sock adder struct remember
参数是一个袜子加法器结构记
for this lecture and I think in the book
这堂讲座， 我觉得在这本书
in a few places we've sort of created a
在一些地方，我们已经有点 创建
type def to alias so we don't have to
高清输入别名 ，所以我们不必
say struct sock adder all over the place
说结构袜子 加法器所有的地方
that's what the essay is and it will
这就是 作文是，它会
provide back information about that that
背部提供有关信息
address so if you passing in a 32 bit IP
地址，所以如果你在一个32位的IP传递
address you can get it to return either
解决你能得到它返回要么
a dotted decimal version of that or to
该人或一个 点分十进制 版本
do the DNS lookup and have it come back
做DNS查找，并将它回来
with the domain name for that
与域名为
so this is that program that I just
所以这是一个程序，我只是
demoed to you this one called host info
向全世界展示你这个叫主机信息
so all it's really going to do is use
因此，所有它的真正要做的是使用
these features to all on the command
这些功能 上的所有命令
line give a domain name say and it will
行给出一个域名称，它会
just come back with a list of IP
刚回来与 IP 列表
addresses so and this is pretty much the
解决 如此 ，这 是相当多的
way you write code for this get a tour
这样，你写的代码为 这个获得旅游
info API that you typically so hints is
信息API，你通常这样的提示
the information I'm passing about what
我传递有关的信息是什么
it is I'm looking for here and so you
这是我在寻找 在这里 ，所以你
start typically by zeroing out that
通过清空，通常开始
entire field and then setting the
整个场，然后设置
particular things you want
你要特别的东西
so in particular in this code that's
所以特别是在这段代码中的
that in the slides and the one I demoed
在幻灯片和一个我演示了
to you last time I'm only going to be
你最后一次我只打算是
looking for ipv4 connections and so I
寻找 IPv4连接，所以我
use the constant called AF I net which
使用所谓的AF我净常数
is defined in the sockets interface and
在套接字接口定义和
also I'll say that I want a TCP
还我会说我想要一个TCP
connection what's called a socket stream
连接什么叫做流套接字
which if you recall is the sort of
其中，如果你还记得是 何许
protocol that 99% of the IP traffic in
协议的 IP 流量 的99％的
the world is carrying is on TCP meaning
世界上正在进行的基于TCP的意义
it provides a somewhat higher level
它提供了略微更高的水平
abstraction of what's going on of
这是怎么回事的抽象
sending packets back and forth so that's
发送数据包来回，这样的
as much hint as I'm giving it here and
尽可能多的提示，我在这里给它和
now I'm I'm making a call to get adder
我现在我正在打电话让加法器
info and this argument is the name which
信息和这种说法是 它 的名称
is I'm getting it right off of the
在我得到 它马上的
command line here so in my demo it was
此命令行 ，以便在我的演示是
always a commit up a domain name I'm
总是犯了一个域名 ，我
passing in null for the service as I
传入null的服务为我
mentioned this call you typically have
提到这个叫你通常有
one of the two are is null but not both
二者之一是为空但不同时
hints is what I'm passing in is this is
提示就是我传递是，这是
the kind of information I want and list
我想要的那种信息和名单
P is a will now become a pointer to the
P是现在将 成为一个指向
results that get returned by get adder
是那些获得由get加法器返回的结果
info
信息
so that's the calling all of its quarry
所以这就是调用它的所有采石场
okay and now I want to go back so I got
好吧 ，现在我要回去 ，所以我就
one of those linked lists and that will
这些链表和意志的一个
have a whole bunch of IP address of
有一大堆的IP地址
potentially multiple IP addresses in it
在它潜在地多个IP地址
maybe just one maybe none but some
也许只是一个 也许没有，但一些
number of them in a link twist and I
他们中的链接 扭曲和我数
want to walk through that list and get
希望通过该列表走路，并得到
back the dotted decimal version of all
备份所有的 点分十进制版本
those names or the colon eyes of those
这些名字或者那些结肠眼睛
ipv6 addresses I don't know how you
IPv6地址我不知道你怎么样
refer to those by the way
是指那些由路
I know relatively little about ipv6 I
我知道比较少有关IPv6的我
have to confess so then there's a
必须承认，这样的话有一个
function called get name info which
函数名为get名信息这
usually you use to take a socket address
通常你使用采取套接字 地址
IP address and go backward and get a
IP地址和留后路，并得到一个
domain name but if I tell it by a flag
域名，但如果我用一个标志告诉它
one of the the final argument to it is a
在最后一个参数 给它的一个是
flag argument and say what I want back
标志参数和说什么，我想回去
from this is not a donut main name I
从这个不是 一个甜甜圈主的名字我
wanted in this numeric format either
在这个数字格式要么通缉
dotted decimal or the Cohen's between
点分十进制或 科恩之间
hex digits so by passing that to get
十六进制数字通过传递，为了得到
name itself what it's going to return
名字本身什么它会 返回
and I'm passing in a buffer meaning a
而我传递一个缓冲区意义
care star and some size of that buffer
护理明星和缓冲区的大小一些
and it's going to fill that in with the
而这将填补 与
string representation of it so you see
它的 字符串 表示，所以你看
this is the way I'm going from the if
这是我从去是否方式
you look at this is the actual sock
你看这是实际的袜子
adder of each of the list elements I'm
每个列表中的元素，我的加法器
giving it it's going from that sock
给它它从袜子去
adder which embedded within it as you
其嵌入在你加法器
know it's the for by IP address and what
知道这是由IP地址和什么
it's doing is it's taking that flipping
它做的是它 采取的是翻转
the bytes well and converting it to the
字节阱并将其转换到
dotted decimal form so this function can
点分十进制形式，以便该功能可
do a lot of different things and I'm
做了很多不同的 东西，我
using it for that particular feature
使用它的特定功能
here question so regarded
这里的问题所以认为
peaceful if he is no then I will go very
和平，如果他不那么我会走的很
far
远
yep because you know it's a
是的，因为你知道这是一个
null-terminated whisk so other questions
空值终止拂所以其他问题
good questions but that's exactly the
好问题，但是这也正是
code you saw running and all I did to
代码，你看到的运行，我所做的 ，以
generalize it to include ipv6 addresses
推广到包括IPv6地址
was I commented out this one say I don't
被我注释掉这一个说 我不
I don't demand that it be a IP IFI net
我不要求它是一个IP IFI网
is a shorthand for ipv4 so by commenting
是对IPv4的简写 这样的评论
that out it said okay I'll get whatever
说出来也说 没关系，我会得到什么
TCP connections this domain will support
TCP连接该域名将支持
and that will include ipv6 addresses so
并且，其中将包括IPv6地址等等
I thought it's pretty neat and you have
我认为这是相当整洁，你必须
to be a pretty nerdy but I am pretty
是一个很差劲的人，但我很
nerdy to think this kind of thing is
书呆子认为这种 事情是
neat but that you could write code and
整洁，但你可以写代码和
in this way that whether you're doing
在这种方式，无论你做
you know different versions of the
你知道不同版本的
internet protocol it's all one common
互联网协议这一切都一个共同的
body of code so we've seen demo of this
的代码体，所以我们看到的这个演示
okay so now let's jump into that shows
好了，现在让我们跳进那个节目
you sort of a little bit of this get
您排序的GET操作 的一点点
adder info API now let's jump into the
加法信息API 现在让我们跳进
the full-blown web server part and as I
在全面的web 服务器部分和我
mentioned in chronological order you
按时间顺序提到你
actually want to set up the server first
其实想先设置服务器
but it's easiest to understand the code
但它是最容易理解的代码
for the client because as you see it has
客户端因为当你看到它有
a couple fewer calls to make so let's go
一对夫妇更少的调用，使让我们 去
for through the client just imagine that
通过客户端 试想 一下 ，
somewhere out there there's a server
在某处，有一个服务器
that's waiting for us to connect to
是在等待 我们 连接到
so this now doesn't perhaps when you
所以这个现在不也许当你
break it down maybe this picture looks a
打破它，也许这张照片看起来
little less daunting
少艰巨
we already saw get editor info is the
我们已经看到了获得 编辑的信息是
way I'm going to get an IP address out
办法，我要出去 获取IP地址
of whatever I'm where my server is
什么的，我在我的服务器
socket I mentioned this yesterday or
插座我这个 昨天 提到 或
last time it's just a local call that
最后一次，它只是一个本地呼叫
used to allocate some data structures
用于分配一些数据结构
for this particular connection and then
对于这个特殊的 连接，然后
connect is like placing a call it's an
连接是例如拨打电话这是一个
API it's actually sending over the
API 它的实际发送过
Internet to the server some information
互联网服务器 的一些信息
saying hey I'd like to connect to you
他说，嘿，我想连接 到 你
and then once the server of risk that
然后一旦风险的服务器
once that connection is accepted then I
一旦 连接被接受，然后 我
can begin my session so let's look at
可以开始 我的会议，以便让我们来 看看
that so first of all I have to go
那所以首先我得走了
through all this rigmarole would get a
通过这一切的繁琐程序会得到一个
tour info but it will look pretty
游览信息，但它的外观 漂亮
similar to what you've seen before
类似于 您之前所看到的
except I'm going to give a little more
除了我要给多一点
information because I want this to be
信息 ，因为我想这是
I'm filling in a few more details here
我填写一些细节在这里
because I want to specify more features
因为我想指定更多的功能
of this connection so I'm saying that
这方面的，所以我说，
it's a TCP connection that's a sock
这是一个TCP连接，这是一个袜子
stream I'm saying that I'm going to give
流I是说，我要去给
it a port number in a numeric form you
它以数字形式的端口，也
could also say as I mentioned of the
也可以说，正如我所说的
certain ports have standard names HTTP
某些端口具有标准名称HTTP
SSH and so forth and you can actually
SSH等等实际上 ，你 可以
pass in the string representation of
传递的字符串表示
those but I'm using this in a sort of
这些，但我在一种使用这种
idiosyncratic way here and then this
在这里，然后这种奇特的方式
feature get adder configures of a
功能得到的加法器提供配置
parameter that described in the book and
书中描述的参数和
they say it's a good idea to use it and
他们说， 这是一个 好 主意 ，用 它 和
then I'm making a call to my friend get
然后我正在给我的朋友打电话让
adder info with these hints and it's
这些提示和它的加法信息
going to return back this link twist of
要恢复 回的这个环节扭曲
representing the the results of this
代表这个结果
request so basically a link twist of IP
要求所以 基本上 IP 的 链接 扭曲
addresses
地址
so now just like you saw before I'm
所以现在就像你看到的，我之前
going to walk that list with a except
要在这个列表里有除
now what I'm going to try and do is for
现在我什么都尝试做是
each of those say well here's the number
每个 那些 说好了，这里的数
let me give that a try and if that fails
让我给一个尝试 ，如果失败
here's another address let me give that
这里的另一个地址，让我给那个
a try so I'm going to do sequentially
一个尝试 ，所以我打算 做的顺序
try all the different addresses you saw
尝试所有你看到的不同的地址
for example for potential addresses for
例如 ， 对于潜在的地址
Twitter I'll walk through all of those
Twitter的，我会通过所有这些走
and on each one I'm going to call for a
和每一个我要打电话了
socket and the socket is the one that as
插座和插座是一个为
I said it allocates some data structures
我说分配一些数据结构
I talked about this last time that's why
我讲到 这最后 的时光，这就是 为什么
I'm rushing to is pretty fast but you'll
我抢着是 相当快 ，但你会
notice that the fields that you're
会注意到你 的 领域
filling in are actually all been
填写实际上 全部被
generated for us by the get adder info
由加法器获取的信息对我们产生
call so whereas the east' have to
调用，这样 ， 而 东”有
remember oh this is the number and it
记住哦，这是数量和 其
should be a shortened network order and
应该是缩短的网络顺序和
yada da pretty much nowadays you can
亚达达几乎现在 就可以
just say here I'm just going to pass you
只是在这里说我只是要 与你擦肩而过
this information that this
这个信息，这
was returned by a function call and then
通过函数调用，然后回到
as I mentioned also last time I know I
像我上次提到的，我知道我
went through a pretty fast last time
通过一个非常快的最后 一次去
socket actually returns back to you a
实际上插座返回到 你
file descriptor and you recall a file
文件描述符 和 调出一个文件
descriptor is just a small integer
描述只是一个小的整数
starts with 0 1 & 2 and then it goes up
与0 1＆2开始 ，然后将其上升
from there and so I'm going to interface
从那里，所以我打算接口
with this network code as if I'm talking
与此 网络代码，如果我说的
through files but it doesn't socket
通过文件，但它并没有插座
doesn't actually do anything as far as
实际上并没有做 任何事情，只要
the internet goes there's nothing going
互联网去没有什么打算
there's not even the no serious effort
有没有 连 没有认真的努力
within the operating system nothing goes
内部操作系统一切 正常
over the network here so the real work
通过网络在这里做到了真正的工作
here is but it also allocates some some
在这里，但它也分配了一些些
local data structures and then what I'll
本地数据结构，然后我会
do is I'll attempt to connect to the
做的是，我会尝试连接到
server and again you'll see the various
服务器并再次，你会看到 各种
arguments I have to pass to the connect
参数我要传递给 连接
command I get provided for me out of
我得到为我提供了命令
this call I made to get editor info and
这个电话我就该好好编辑信息 和
that's either going to work or it's not
这要么去上班或者它不是
going to work similarly the socket calls
将同样的工作套接字 调用
either going to work or not work be very
无论是上班或 不能正常工作是非常
unusual for a call to socket to fail but
不寻常的 呼叫套接字失败，但
connect for example will fail if the
连接例如，如果将失败
server's not available or doesn't like
服务器不可用或不喜欢
you for some reason and so if that
你出于 某种原因 ，并因此，如果这
succeeds I'm going to break out of this
成功我要打破这个
loop I'm going to then free this data
循环 我要去然后释放此数据
structure and return the client the file
构建并返回 客户端的文件
descriptor for the this particular
描述了这个特殊的
function it's job is to open a
发挥 它的工作是开一家
connection to a client and return a file
连接到客户端 ，并返回一个文件
descriptor for it and this is just what
描述了它，这正是
happens if you fall out of the loop not
如果你掉出 循环 不发生
having made any connection
在作出任何连接
okay so I know this is a marching this
好了，所以我知道这是一个踏着 这
fast and as I said I know from my own
快和我说，我从我自己知道
personal experience I can attest this
个人的经验，我可以证明这
stuff just takes time to understand
东西只是需要时间来了解
because there's so many different
因为有这么多的不同
features here okay but that's the idea
此功能不错 ，但是这样的想法
is we're going to now on the server side
是我们现在要在服务器端
which as I mentioned is that actually
这正如我所说 的 是 ，实际上
what you do beforehand because you can't
你事先做什么，因为你不能
really have a client connect to a server
真的有一个客户端连接到服务器
that doesn't exist but it's just a
不 存在的，但它只是一个
little bit trickier to understand what's
有点棘手 ，了解哪些
going on but you'll see it the first two
怎么回事，但你会看到它的前两个
steps are the same I need a socket but
步骤是 我需要一个插座 ，但 相同
then remember what I want to do is
然后记得我想要做的是
essentially set up a server that
基本上建立了一个服务器
listening on a particular port for
侦听特定端口上
clients to request on it and that's the
客户端请求就可以了，这就是
function of the bind in the wissen
在 WISSEN 绑定的功能
functions and then the accept is when
功能再 接受的是，当
I'm saying okay the server is ready I'm
我说没关系的服务器 准备好我
ready to accept requests and it will
准备好接受请求，它会
fire that up in particular the accept
火，截至尤其是接受
will just stop and hang up and wait
将刚刚停止，挂起并等待
indefinitely until some connection
无限期，直到一定的联系
request comes in so if the server has no
请求进来所以，如果服务器没有
customers if there are no clients it
客户如果没有它的客户端
will just be waiting potentially forever
将只是可能永远等待
with the call to accept okay everything
与呼叫接受 好一切
else goes through boom boom boom but
否则经过嘣嘣嘣但
that one is where the actual waiting
一个是实际的等待在那里
occurs for client connections
发生客户端连接
some way I should mention the Kinect
一些方法，我应该提的Kinect
will also hang up and wait until the
也将自动挂断，等待
connection is formed but typically it's
连接形成，但通常它是
built in with a timeout so that it will
内置了超时 ，这样它会
fail if it takes too long and you can
如果采取故障太长，你可以
adjust the parameters on both of these
调整上这两个参数
how long you wait for whether your
多久你等着您是否
weight enough but I'm talking the
重量不够好，但我说的
typical case so anyways again what will
典型情况下，所以反正又会有什么
look a little those functions then okay
看起来有点这些功能，然后好吗
so this again we have to make a call to
所以这一次，我们必须做出一个电话
get edit info and this time it's not
获取编辑信息，这一次它不是
because I need any IP addresses I
因为我需要的任何IP地址我
already have an IP address I'm a local
已经有一个IP地址，我是一个地方
server I don't actually need to know the
服务器我实际上并不需要 知道
IP addresses of my of the client so I
客户端的我的 IP 地址，所以我
usually won't know them but I need to
通常不知道他们，但我需要
fill in all those nasty little data
填写所有这些讨厌的 小数据
structures and so that's what I'm going
结构等，这就是我要去
to use get adder info here for here so
使用获得的信息法器这里这里 这么
I'm going to say this time again I want
我要去我想再次说这个时间
a TCP connection a sock stream I want it
一个TCP 连接 的袜子流，我希望它
to be a listening for any IP address
因任何IP地址的监听
connection coming in so it's passive
连接进来的所以很被动
meaning it's not actively reaching out
这意味着它不会主动伸手
it's passively waiting for connection
它是被动地 等待连接
requests I'll say that I'm going to tell
请求我说，我要 告诉
you a port number that I'm going to
你说我要一个端口号
actually use as my servers port number
其实我的服务器端口号使用
and then I'm going to make a call and
然后我要拨打电话和
this time you see that I'm not giving
这时候你看到， 我不会放弃
any information about the host because I
有关主机 ，因为 我的任何信息
am the host but I'm giving the
我的主人，但我给了
information of the port number that I'm
我是端口号的信息
using for this server and the other
使用此服务器和其他
hints that I've just filled in and then
暗示，我刚刚填写，然后
it will return a wispy yes memset is the
它会返回一个纤细的是 memset的是
standard way that you set all the bytes
您设置的所有字节的标准方式
in in some number of bytes to a fixed
在一些数目 的字节到固定
value it's the same as if you've use B 0
价值是一样的，如果你已经采用 B 0
before or B it was is the way you often
之前或B是为你经常的方式
would zero out a bunch of bytes and if
将零出一堆字节，如果
you look at the web page and I don't
你看一下网页，我不
know why they say use memset don't use B
知道他们为什么说用memset的不使用B钮
0 anymore so callous Walt to do it out
0了，所以无情 沃尔特 做出来
but I'm not actually eleking anything
但我实际上没有什么艾雷金刚
see the hints is a struct here and
看到提示是一个结构和这里
remember is struct is just a bunch of
记住的是结构的只是一堆
bytes and so if I make that particular
字节， 如果我做的是如此特别
call to memset it will set every byte in
调用memset的 它会在设定的每一个字节
that structure to 0 and this is sort of
该结构为 0，这 是有点
the official standard way you're
你是官方的标准方式
supposed to do that kind of thing so
应该做 那种事情，所以
it's a good question so question hey I
这是一个很好的问题， 所以问题嘿，我
pass of is that it's a it's a listening
传递的是，它是一个这是一个 听音
connection it's going to be a listening
连接这将是一个监听
connection and a I adder config was some
连接和我加法器配置为一些
other argument and quite honestly I
其他参数，并坦白地说我
don't remember but you saw I gave it
不记得了，但你看到 我给它
before with the get host name so I don't
用get 主机名之前， 所以我不知道
remember it's it's a somewhat obscure
记住这是这是一个有点模糊
per parameter that's not even a required
每个参数甚至不是一个必需的
parameter it's in the book I'm sorry or
参数是在书里我很抱歉或
you could google it right now
你现在可以google一下
one interesting thing is I didn't say
一个有趣的事情是我没有说
that on this code on either side that
上 在任一侧 该代码
it's a Fi net I didn't force this to be
这是一个 Fi网络我没有强迫 这 是
I CV for code this will work for ipv4 or
我的简历代码这会 为IPv4 或 工作
six the exact same code
六完全相同的代码
okay so again whispy comes back with a
好了，所以再次whispy回来了
list of stuff typically that list will
东西列表通常该列表会
be of length one in fact I don't know
是长度为一， 其实 我也不知道
why it would be anything else but it has
为什么它会是任何 东西，但它有
the same general look to it so again I'm
同一般 看它，因此再次，我
going to make a call to socket to create
要拨打电话，以Socket创建
a file descriptor that I'm going to use
我打算使用一个文件描述符
this will be the one that it lists the
这将是 它列出了 一
server listens on of your connection
服务器监听你的连接
requests and then there's another kind
请求，然后还有另一种
of obscure thing you have to do of
不起眼的事情，你必须做的
setting some options on that socket that
设置套接字的一些选项
will get it to free it up more quickly
会得到它来释放它更快
if there's a failure it's this is gone
如果有一个故障是这是走了
this one I dunno and it's kind of
这个我不知道，它是一种
obscure and it's in the book so I won't
模糊的，它是在这本书，所以我不会
spend a lot of time talking about it
花了很多时间谈论它
okay but now what here's the real work
还好，但 现在这里有什么真正的工作
is the bind call is the one that says I
是绑定呼叫，说我一个
want this file descriptor to be
希望这个文件描述符是
associated with this information which
与此相关联的信息，其
in particular specifies the port number
特别指定的端口号
so that's where the binding occurs for
因此，这就是绑定 的发生
this machine
这台机器
remember port numbers are a resource
记住端口号是一个资源
that all the different applications on a
所有 在 不同的应用程序
single machine are sort of sharing or
单台机器的排序或共享
are competing for and so this is
正在竞争，因此这是
requesting I want to use this particular
请求我想用这种特殊
port number in doing this in setting up
在建立这样的端口号
a server and that may fail if the ports
一台服务器， 如果端口可能会失败
already in use or if you're trying to
已经使用，或如果你想
set up a service on a port that you're
建立一个服务，你是一个端口上
not allowed to do like you're not
不允许做这样你不
allowed to set up a service on port 80
允许 设立一个服务端口80上
unless you have root access
除非你有root 权限
so and then again it passes in the
因此，然后再它通过在
information that was filled in by the
这是由填写信息
call to get a tour info so we're not
打电话来获得旅游信息 ，以便我们 不
quite done yet
完全 完成 ， 但
but we if this succeeds then what we've
但我们如果成功那么我们已经
done is we've found a port number and a
做的是，我们已经找到了一个端口号和
file descriptor together and a socket
文件描述符一起和插座
but it all that's done is that's again
但是这一切都这样做了的是，我们再次
just within the machine saying okay I
只是机器 说好吧，我 内
agree you you you particularly this
同意你你你这个特别
particular process gets to be listening
特定的工艺得到在听
on a particular port but it's not
一个特定的端口，但它不是
actually listening yet and I don't know
实际收听但 我不 知道
why they split it into two but they do
他们为什么把它分解成两个，但他们做的
and now I actually have to explicitly
现在我居然要明确
make a call to listen saying okay now I
拨打电话现在听 他说好吧，我
really am ready to receive connection
真的很愿意接收连接
requests and you can give as a parameter
请求 你可以给作为参数
of a number that says how many requests
的一定数量的多少请求 说：
connection requests are you allowed to
连接请求您允许
queue up before they start getting
排队，他们开始 得到 前
refused and this is a performance
拒绝，这是一款性能
parameter that if you set it to low then
参数， 如果你把它设置 为低，然后
unless you have a really fast server
除非你有一个 非常快速的服务器
people will get failures in their
人们会得到失败在他们的
connection requests but if it's too big
连接请求，但如果它太大
then you can you're vulnerable to
那么你就可以很 容易
certain types of sort of denial of
某些类型的那种拒绝的
service attacks so again a little bit of
服务攻击如此反复一点点
an obscure feature but the result of
一个不起眼的功能，但结果
this is now I'm returning out of this a
这是现在我回来了这一个的
file descriptors as the server can use
文件描述符服务器可以使用
to listen to pick up connection requests
听拿起连接请求
okay so let's do a little example of how
好了，让我们做 的怎么样 一个 小例子
we might actually do something and I'm
我们 实际上可能会做一些事情， 我
going to use as an example a rather
要作为一个例子来使用一个相当
mundane application which is an echo
平凡应用程序，它是回声
server an echo server is just one that
服务器回声服务器只是 一个
responds back whatever it just received
返回响应不管它刚刚收到
and the code for it in the book on the
并在本子上 它的代码
slides we're studying
幻灯片我们正在 研究
so let me set up this amazing
因此，让我成立这个惊人
demonstration
示范
so it's called the echo server I I
因此，它被称为回声服务器II
meaning iterative it can only do one
这意味着迭代它只能做一
connection request at a time and I'm
同时连接请求 和我
going to set it up on my laptop here and
要在这里设置它在我的笔记本电脑
I'll connect to that so you'll see that
我将连接到，所以你会看到，
I told the server use port 15 to 13
我告诉服务器使用端口15至13
which is just a random number I picked
这仅仅是 我挑选 一个 随机数
out as the port number in general if you
作为出一般的端口号 ，如果你
want to do your own stuff you pick port
想要做自己的东西，你挑口
numbers that are a thousand or greater
这是一千或更多数量的
and they're limited to be unsigned
而且他们限定为 无符号
16-bit int so 64 65,000 something some
16位int所以64 65000 一些东西
maximum and as long as and by the way if
最大而且只要通过万一途中
you're you live in a corporate world
你是你生活在一个商业 世界
your ports will all be locked down and
你的端口都将被锁定，
they will not let you do this but in the
他们不会让你这样做，但在
CMU environment has a pretty permissive
CMU环境有一个非常宽容
policy and actually I'm just doing this
政策，实际上我只是 在做这
on localhost but you're allowed to at
在本地主机，但你被允许在
CMU open up ports like you want so
CMU打开端口像你想的那么
anyways I'm going to run this client and
反正我要运行这个客户机和
you'll see that the server just said
你会看到，服务器只是说
I've received a connection from the
我已经收到了一个连接
localhost not very exciting and I've
本地主机 不是很兴奋，我已经
received it from port five five four
从端口 五五四人获其
five seven so this is the part that got
五七所以这是 得到了 这个角色
assigned to the client in making the
分配给客户端在使
connection the server is using port 15
连接服务器正在使用端口15
to 13 and you recall we talked about
13，你还记得我们谈到
last time that a link is defined by the
一个链接被定义的最后一次
host and port names on either end and
在两端主机和端口的名称和
that the client side is usually assigned
客户端侧通常被 分配
what they call it ephemeral port meaning
他们把它叫做临时端口的含义
it's just assigned for this particular
它只是分配给这个特殊的
session that I'm going to run and now
我要去跑，现在会议
here's the amazing feature of an echo
这里有回声的惊人的特点
server is that you can type in stuff and
服务器是， 你可以在东西型和
it will come back to you
它会回来给你
because echoing so what's happening is
因为呼应所以发生了什么事是
I'm sending those meaningful messages to
我要送那些有意义的消息
the server it's reading them and it's
服务器时，它的阅读他们，这是
just send him right back again and then
只是送他右后卫 再次，然后
the clients reading that and printing it
客户端读取和打印出来
on the screen so that it's not it's a
在屏幕上， 这样它不是这是一个
sort of the minimum functionality you
排序的最小功能，您
could imagine but you can see that the
可以想像，但你可以看到 ，
server is telling you oh by the way I
服务器是在告诉你哦，顺便说一下我
just received so many bytes so many
刚刚收到这么多 字节，因此很多
bytes so many bytes so you can see that
字节，因此多少字节，所以你可以看到，
it's actually doing something and then
它实际上做的东西，然后
if I send it into file which is just a
如果我把它变成文件，该文件仅仅是一个
control D the client will exit and the
控制D中的客户端将退出并
server will drop that connection but
服务器将丢弃连接，但
doesn't show you anything and if I
不告诉你任何东西，如果我
wanted to I could start it again and you
希望我能再次启动它，你
see this time it signed a different
看到这一次签约不同
ephemeral port to the client but I can
临时端口的 客户端，但我可以
only do one at a time if I tried to now
只能做一次一个，如果我现在试着
do another connection I will try and do
做另一个方面， 我会尝试做
it if I tried to do it I wouldn't I
它如果我试图做到这一点 我就没有我
would just hang up the client would hang
只想挂上客户端会挂起
up it would not be able to get a
起来，将无法获得
connection because the server is only
连接，因为服务器只
able to handle one client at a time okay
能够一次处理一个客户端好吗
so that's the what the application does
所以这是该应用做什么
and now let's see how its implemented
现在让我们来看看它是如何 实现的
so it's pretty simple that the nastiness
所以这是非常简单 的污秽
was those functions we've already seen
是我们已经看到这些功能
so here's the clients side of it it
所以这里是它的客户端它
calls that function I went through
调用函数 我经历了
called open the client file descriptor
所谓开放客户端的文件描述符
where you gave the name of the host and
在这里你给了主机的名称和
the name of the port that you're the
港口是你的名字
server's operating on so I said here
服务器的，所以我在这里说操作
localhost 15 to 13 and I'm going to
本地主机15到13， 我要
initialize a buffer that will be used
初始化将要使用的缓冲
for communication back and forth for
通信来回
this network communication so now
该网络通信所以现在
echoing means I from a client
呼应意味着 我从客户端
perspective it will just read in what
角度来看，这将 刚读什么
I've typed so using get s or F get s to
我键入的内容，以便使用get S或 F得到 s 到
read in what's been typed on the
读什么被键入的
standard input and as long as that not
标准的输入 ，只要 不是
null meaning I don't have a end of file
空的意思我 没有 文件 的末尾
then I will write it to the client file
然后，我将它写入到客户机文件
descriptors so that's how I actually
描述所以这就是我怎么竟
send it over the network as I do a write
把它 在网络 上 像我这样写
to that
到
socket that that file descriptor
插口，该文件描述符
represents and then to get something
代表，然后得到的东西
back from the server its response I'll
从服务器的响应后， 我会
do a read and Rio as you call is
做一个读和里奥您拨打的
embedded within it
嵌入其中
what file descriptor that read is using
什么文件描述符，上面写着正在使用
so I'll say read from that particular
所以我会说，从该特定阅读
file descriptor fill the results back
文件描述符填写结果反馈
into this buffer so I'm using buff both
到这个缓冲区 ，所以我使用 这两个BUFF
as a sending buffer and a receiving
作为发送缓冲器和接收
buffer and then just print that out onto
缓冲区，然后只打印 出到
the on to the terminal and this is by
在到终端，这是由
the way the new lines being included in
被包括在新线 的 方式
this not just the in all of this so
这不只是在所有这一切使
that's how it it's working so that's all
这就是它它是如何工作，所以这一切
that happens so the main point you see
出现这种情况，所以你看到的要点
here is that I'm using this socket like
下面是我使用这个插座一样
a file to both send and receive
文件同时发送和接收
the server code is just a shade more
服务器代码仅仅是一个树荫 多
nasty than that to support some of those
讨厌的比来 支持一些人的
amazing features it has so in particular
神奇功能，它有那么特别
there's a weird struct called a socket
有一个称为套接字怪异的结构
or storage that is just again part of
或存储，只是再次的一部分
this generic API that gives you a buffer
这个通用API，让你一个缓冲
of some kind that's big enough to store
某种这是 足够 大 的存储
a name of a host is what I'm going to
主办方的名字是什么我要去
use it for you and so I'm going to
使用它 你，所以我要去
accept a connection so except recall you
接受连接，因此 除非你召回
recall is the way it it says okay I'm
召回的方式，它说好了我
going to wait here until a client
要在 这里等到客户端
contacts this server so that you make a
接触此服务器， 让 你做一个
call to accept and it will just hang
叫接受，它会挂
until that contact occurs and then what
直到发生该联系人，然后什么
it will return from you is a new file
它将返回从你的是一个新的文件
descriptor that we call a connection
描述， 我们称之为连接
file descriptor here which is different
这里文件描述符是不同的
from the listening file descriptor and
从监听的文件描述符和
the reason is doesn't really show up in
原因是 并没有真正出现在
this code where I'm doing iteratively
这个代码，我正在做迭代
but you can imagine if I had a server
但你能想象如果我有 一台服务器
and I wanted to be able to maintain a
我希望能够保持
thousand connections at once so be one
在一次千元的连接，所以要一个
of those file descriptors that I pick up
我拿起 这些文件描述符
new requests on and then all the other
新的请求，然后所有其他
ones are the various other clients that
的有其他各种客户端
I'm communicating with right now and
我与沟通，现在和
then what accept fills in here into this
那么什么接受罢了，这里这个
information that's a sock adder struct
这是一个袜子加法器结构 信息
is about information about the client
大约是关于客户 信息
the IP address of the client
客户端的 IP地址
and I'll use this call called get name
我会使用 这个调用名为get名
info which is again at one of these
信息这又是其中之一
kitchen sink features that I'll pass in
厨房水槽的功能，我会通过在
this client address and it will come
此客户端地址，它会来
back with the ice the domain name of the
回来与冰的域名
client and that's what you saw how it
客户端，这就是你看到 它是 如何
printed out when the connection is
打印出当连接
formed where that connection is coming
形成在该连接来
from so this all this business here is
来自所以这一切这项业务是在这里
used to support that feature of being
用来支持 被 该功能
able to print out what's the host number
能够打印出什么是主机号
name and what port am I using and this
名字和我使用的端口，这
thing by the way client port is a host
顺便说一下 客户端的是一台主机
name and client port are both buffers
名称和客户端是两个缓冲区
yes host name and port are both buffers
是的主机名和端口都缓冲器
and I'm passing a pointer those buffers
而我传递一个指针这些缓冲区
and I'm passing their length max wine
而我路过他们的长度最长的酒
and then the call to get name info it's
然后调用get 名信息是
filling those in with a string
用字符串填充那些在
representations of the host name and the
主机名和交涉
port
港口
and now it just makes a call to the echo
现在它只是使回声通话
function which I'll show you momentarily
功能，我会告诉你瞬间
and then it closes that connection and
然后关闭该连接和
then this continues you see the wild one
那么这样下去，你看到一个野
this is in a loop forever and you
这是一个死循环，你
actually have to control see on this
其实要控制 看 这个
program to get it to quit okay so let me
程序让它退出 好了，让我
just click one more
只需点击一个 更
so the funk this now is the echo
所以芬克这是现在的回声
function that the server uses and it's
功能服务器使用，它的
pretty straightforward in fact it looks
很简单 ， 其实它看起来
kind of like what you just saw except it
有点像你刚才除了它看到
flips around the reading and the writing
翻转阅读和写作围绕
it will read some number of bytes over
它会 在 读取一定数量的 字节，
the connection file descriptor and if
连接文件描述符，如果
that's a nonzero number then it will
这是一个非零数字，然后它会
echo that back by writing it if it's a
回声是回来写它，如果它是一个
zero that means it's detected and into
零，这意味着 它的检测和 成
file and it will just exit from that
文件，它会从刚刚退出
little loop but remember echo is within
小环却记得回声内
a bigger loop of accepting new
接受新的更大的环
connection requests okay but again just
连接请求不错，但 只是 一次
see that it reads is a way of accepting
看到它的内容是接受 的一种方式
information from the client and then it
从客户端，然后它的信息
writes to send information back to the
写入信息发送回
client
客户
good so one interesting feature is if
好，因此一个有趣的特点是，如果
you want to test some programs you can
你想测试一些程序，你可以
use a program called telnet which it
使用程序调用远程登录，它
used to be the old-fashioned way you use
曾经是你使用老式的方法
before SSH this is how you communicated
SSH之前，你这是怎么沟通
with other machines and it's absolutely
与其他机器 ，它的绝对
completely insecure so don't ever use it
完全不安全所以永远不要使用它
to X and most most places you can't even
X和最大多数地方 ，你甚至不能
make a connection to another machine
令 到另一台机器 的连接
using telnet it's amazing how simple
使用telnet 令人惊讶的是简单
life used to be
生活曾经是
but for example if I tell nut to myself
但例如，如果我告诉 螺母对自己
on that port
在该端口上
it will begin a session and it will in
它将开始一个会话 ，它会在
fact look a lot like an echo client
其实很像回声 客户端
because because telnet just sends
因为由于远程登录只是将
information to the server and the server
信息到服务器，服务器
is designed to echo it back and so it
旨在呼应回来，所以它
will print the response and so if
将打印响应， 因此，如果
actually telnet is behaving like an echo
实际上Telnet是表现得像一个回波
client for me and I'll demo that because
客户端的我，我会演示，由于
it's useful I mean this is a pretty
它是有用 的意思，这是一个相当
trivial program but there's actually
琐碎的程序，但实际上有
times you can use telnet if there's a
有时你可以使用telnet，如果有 一个
server somewhere out there and you want
服务器的地方在那里，你想
to give it a poke to see what's going on
给它一捅， 看看这是怎么回事
as a tool you can use telnet let's say
作为一个工具，你可以使用telnet让我们说
you have to escape with a control right
你 有一个控制权 逃脱
bracket quick okay so now let's move on
支架快好了，现在让我们继续前进
to http
到http
I try to get rid of all the animations
我试图摆脱 所有的动画
in this okay so that's sort of the
在这样行，这样的排序的
basics of the low-level socket
低级别的插座的基本知识
programming that you need to create
编程，你 需要创建
client-server applications so the best
客户端-服务器应用程序，因此最好
example out there of a client-server
例如在那里客户端 - 服务器的
application is the world wide web and
应用是万维网和
you know the idea web servers and your
你知道这个想法Web 服务器和 您的
browser is a client so but all of that
浏览器是一个客户端，但所有这一切
fits on top of the protocols for that
适合对这些协议的顶部
sit on top of the other internet
坐在其他 互联网 之上
protocols so we talked about TCP is sort
协议，因此我们谈到了TCP 几分
of sits on top of the lowest level the
坐镇上 的最低水平 之上
packet protocol and then HTTP it sits on
分组协议，然后http 它位于
top of that and uses TCP connections to
最重要的 是，并使用TCP连接
send and receive data over the World
在全球信息发送和接收数据
Wide Web and that's all according to a
万维网，这一切根据
protocol that was developed starting in
被开发在起始 协议
the early 90s but and that's what Tim
90年代初，但 ，这 就是蒂姆
Berners Tim berners-lee did initially
伯纳斯蒂姆·伯纳斯-李最初做
and it's gone through a couple revisions
并且它 通过一对夫妇 去 修改
but the latest one and still dates back
但最新的一个，仍然可以追溯到
to 1999 HTTP version
至1999年的HTTP版本
excuse me 1.1 so just is a some
请问1.1所以只是是一些
terminology and you've sort of heard
术语和你有点听过
this at various different ways is you
这在各种不同的方式 是你
can one of the clever things about HTTP
可以在关于HTTP聪明的事情之一
is it lets you search set handles
是它可以让你搜索组句柄
different formats you can send a JPEG
不同的格式， 您 可以发送JPEG
image you can send a a text and so forth
图像可以发送AA文本等等
and those are all encoded in a format
和那些都在格式编码
called mime which is actually just a way
所谓的哑剧这实际上只是一个方式
to take a binary values and convert them
采取二进制值，并将其转换
into hex formatted strings
为十六进制格式的字符串
oh and and then sort of a standard for
噢，然后排序的标准
how you encode it at one end how you
你如何在一端进行编码， 如何
decode it the other and so you get to
解码它的另一等你到了
specify when you're sending stuff you
当你发送的东西，你指定
specify what what type of information it
指定什么什么类型的信息，它
is and then the other thing you've
是和那么你其他的事情
probably experienced in now we're
大概经历了 现在我们
talking a little bit ancient history and
说话有点古老的历史和
all updated momentarily but classically
所有瞬间，但经典的更新
you either use static content meaning a
您既可以使用静态内容含义
fixed web page that was written in HTML
这是用HTML编写的固定网页
format and was designed to just give you
并设计格式 只是给你
information that looks the same every
看起来都一样的信息
time you looked at it or dynamic content
时间你看着它 或动态内容
where you will change so for example a
在那里你会改变，因此例如
application a server application that's
应用服务器的应用程序，是
giving you the weather it's not the same
给你这是不一样的天气
page every time and so it will format it
网页每一次，所以它会格式化
in dynamic content if you make a request
在动态内容，如果你提出要求
nowadays it's gotten a lot more
现在它得到了很多
complicated because of JavaScript and
复杂的，因为JavaScript和的
all these other sort of client-side
所有这些其他类型的客户端的
programming languages that actually
编程语言， 实际上
execute code on your client and
您的客户端上执行代码和
communicates back and forth to get a
通信来回得到
result so I'm a little bit dated here
结果，所以我一点点 过时这里
talking about this sort of old-style way
谈到这种旧式的方式
of working but in all cases what
工作，但在任何情况下什么
actually comes across the wires are some
实际上遇到的电线有一些
type of a file
文件的类型
and then you've heard the term URL
然后，你听说过这个词网址
meaning Universal resource locator is a
意思是统一资源 定位符是
combination of a couple things one is it
一对夫妇的事情之一的组合是它
tells you where is that information in
告诉你哪里是在信息
terms of a domain name and potentially
域名方面和潜在
with the port numbers and then also on
与端口号，然后还
that particular host where we're within
特定主机， 我们是内
the host is that information to be found
主机是 可以 找到 的信息
and there's defaults like if you don't
这里面的，如果你不喜欢默认
give anything it defaults to index.html
给什么它默认的index.html
for example but a URL in principle gives
例如但原则上 一个网址 给
you where to locate something on a
你在哪里可以找到一个东西
remote machine and now we've seen
远程机器，现在我们已经 看到 了
examples of the tricks that DNS plays so
该DNS扮演这样的招数例子
that even though you're giving a
即使你给一个
hostname
主机名
a domain name it could be any of a
域名可以是任何 的
number of different servers but the
不同的 服务器，但 数
concept still the same
概念 仍然是相同的
so when I make a request then when I
所以当我提出要求的时候，然后 我
running my browser and I want to see a
运行我的浏览器，我想看到一个
webpage what it does is it sends an HTTP
网页 什么它是它发送一个HTTP
request out to the server to do
请外面的服务器做
something and to return back a webpage
东西，即可返回 网页
and there's a couple of different
并有一对夫妇的不同
standard services the most common the
标准服务的最常见 的
one that used ninety ninety seven
一个使用 90 97
percent of the time is get get me a page
％的时间是让我拿个网页
and there's other stuff too
这里面的其他东西太多
and then it will respond back with
然后它会回应回来
what's called the response line and
什么叫做 响应行和
embedded within that response will be
嵌入在该响应中会
the thing you're asking for but in front
你问，但眼前的事
of it all is a header that contains
这一切是包含一个头
other stuff that is of of some range of
其他的东西，是一定范围内的
interest of whether you really care or
你是否真的关心或感兴趣
not it can also come back with a
不是也可以回来了
response that says there's an error code
回应，说 有一个错误代码
as you know the infamous 404 error code
正如你所知道 臭名昭著 的 404错误代码
so let me give you a demo of this just
所以让我给你的这只是一个演示
so we're talking a little abstract
所以我们在谈论一个有点抽象
and this is a little tricky to make it
这是一个有点棘手， 使它
work
工作
and I'll use telnet as a way to probe a
我会使用telnet 的方式来探测
webserver so I'll make a telnet
网络服务器，所以我会做 一个telnet
connection to the computer science
连接到计算机科学
department a web server and now I need
部门Web 服务器 ，现在我需要
to make a get request this remember it
做一个GET请求该记住它
all it is is now I'm basically providing
所有这是现在我基本上提供
the exact bytes that will be seen by the
将由可以看到确切的字节
web server so if I say get slash tilde
Web 服务器 ，所以如果我说得到斜线波浪
bryant test dot HTML see if it's really
科比测试 点HTML看看 它 是否 真的
works
作品
I work
我工作
I'm always surprised when things
我总是惊讶的事情
actually work ah
实际工作啊
so anyways let's just look at what
所以反正我们 只是看看
happened so at the top is what I typed
发生这样的顶部是我打字
in it's getting and this I'm giving some
在它变得和这个我给一些
the name of a particular web page that I
特定网页的名称，我
made up just for this purpose a fairly
由只用于此目的 的相当
simple web page and I'm telling it I
简单的网页，我告诉它 我
want the response in the HTTP 1.1 format
要在HTTP 1.1格式的响应
and then I have to also give a hostname
然后我也必须给一个主机名
explicitly and the reason for this is a
明确而这样做的原因是
given machine can actually be served
给定的机器其实是可以服
multiple hosts like if you know I want
多台主机 一样，如果你知道我想
to pay for a hosting of some domain name
支付 一些域名托管服务
say to go daddy.com but it's serving
说去daddy.com 但它的服务
hundreds or thousands of different
成百上千的不同
domain names and so it actually used
域名 ，所以它实际使用
that host information to figure out
该主机的信息弄清楚
which particular web customer am i
其特定的Web客户是我
supporting here ok and now it came back
支持这里确定 ，现在它回来了
with its response and it said the code
与 它的响应 和它说的代码
200 means that was accepted which it
该被接受的装置200，它
tells you ok and now it comes back with
告诉你，OK，现在它回来
this is the header information that says
这是说，头信息
here's the date here's the server here's
这里的日期 这里是这里的服务器
some cookie information it's a the
一些Cookie信息这是一个在
overall content is exactly 479 bytes and
总体内容正是479个字节
it's a text HTML format and then it will
这是一个文本HTML格式，然后它会
return back the raw HTML that this web
返回回原始的 HTML 本网站
page had which is what I actually you
页面有这 就是我其实你
know I typed that I did this by hand but
知道我打我 的 手 这样做 ，但
you can imagine other types of things
你可以想象其他类型的东西
and then it just closes the connection
然后它只是关闭连接
so you can see that it's returned both
所以 你可以看到，它的 两个返回
the header information and the actual
标题信息和实际
content information as well and so that
内容信息以及和使
that's the general idea of what an HTTP
这就是 一个HTTP 的 总体思路
transaction looks like and the slides go
交易貌似和幻灯片去
through a different version of it
通过不同版本的它
but it's the same general idea
但它是相同的总体思路
so the text has a really interesting
所以文本有一个非常有趣
code that I highly recommend you read
代码，我强烈建议你阅读
and study called tiny which is the
并研究称为微小这是
world's smallest functioning webserver
世界上最小的 网络服务器 功能
and what it's really only a couple pages
并且它真的只有几页
of code it serves it says some very
代码 它服务，它说一些很
basic handling of static and dynamic
静态和动态的基本处理
content it's something you can sit down
内容它的东西，你可以坐下来
and read and study 239 lines of code now
和 阅读现在研究239行代码
it lacks a lot of features it does very
它缺乏很多 功能非常不
bad job of handling errors it doesn't
处理错误的坏的工作 它不
have a lot of the functionality you'd
有很多的功能，你会
come to expect in a server so it's been
进来一个服务器 想到 那么它已经
stripped down to the sort of bare bones
剥离下来的那种光秃秃的骨头
to demonstrate the concepts but it's
以展示概念，但它的
pretty cool that it works and I can say
很酷， 它的作品， 我可以 说
this because I didn't write it so so the
这一点，因为我没有 把它 写 这样使
overall idea then is and the cert it's a
所以总体思路是和证书这是一个
server so it's receiving requests from
服务器，以便它接收来自请求
clients from browsers saying I want this
从浏览器的客户说 我要这个
web page or I want to execute this
网页或我要执行此
particular dynamic program to get
特别是动态程序获得
dynamic content so it comes in with a
动态内容，以便其与进来
request get requests like you just saw
请求得到 请求像你刚才看到
and it splits that it picks out the
并将其拆分它挑选出来的
what's called the URI the argument to
什么叫做URI的参数
the get request or URI is a universal
GET请求或URI是一种通用
resource indicator which is not a
资源指示其不是
complete potential of URIs are a super
URI的完整的潜力 是超级
set of URLs URL has to include the
网址 URL 集 已为包括
hostname and all the information to get
主机名和所有 的信息 来获得
from anywhere to anywhere but a URI can
从任何地方到任何地方，但一个URI能
just be a portion of that information
仅仅是该信息的一部分
and then it it will determine is it's a
然后它会决定是它的一个
request for static or dynamic content
请求静态或动态内容
I'll show you both of them hopefully and
我希望告诉你他们与
if it's a static content all it has to
如果它是一个静态内容所有它
do is retrieve a file on its own machine
做的是找回自己的机器上的文件
send that back in that format that I
发送该格式回来，我
just showed you so let's take a look
刚才给你那么让我们来看看
this is sort of the guts of the static
这是那种静态的胆量
server so what it's done is it's
服务器还等什么，它的完成是 它的
received a request this is you know a
接收到一个请求，这是你知道
function a helper function of of this
功能的这样的辅助函数
code so I'm kind of buried down in the
代码，所以我是一种埋在在
middle but what it's picked out is the
中间但什么它挑出来是
server is received a request for a
服务器接收到针对一个请求
particular file name from the URI and
从URI特定文件名 和
it's also done a look up through the OS
它也通过OS做一个查找
call to figure out how big is that file
打电话要弄清楚到底有多大这个文件
how many bytes long is that file and
多少个字节是文件，
it's also given the file descriptor that
它也给定的文件描述符
is the connect the file descriptor for
是连接文件描述符
this particular connection so all it's
这个特殊的连接，因此它所有的
doing here you'll notice is it's doing a
在 这里 做什么 ，你会 发现它是在做一个
bunch of Spirit ups into a buffer and
一群精神跌宕到缓冲区和
what it's doing there is it's formatting
它在做什么有 它的格式
the header information as a byte is just
标题信息作为一个字节仅仅是
a big long string including the the
大长字符串包括 在
returns in it and one of the features
在它的回报和的 特征之一
which don't ask me why the great wisdom
不问我为什么大智慧
of of Tim Berners we did or whoever
的蒂姆·伯纳斯我们做或 谁
figure this out but every line has to
算出来，但每一行有
finish with both a carriage return and a
与两个回车 和完成
new line instead of the usual Linux
新的生产线，而不是 通常的Linux
thing of just new lines so that's what
只是新线的事情，所以这就是
the backslash R backslash n mu but
反斜杠ř反斜杠 Ñ亩但
you'll see it's going to respond back to
你会看到它会 回应回
with an okay and some of this kind of
有 好一些这类的
information that's not very exciting but
这不是很令人兴奋的信息，但
the ones that really matter are are the
对那些 真正的问题是是
length the invites that has to be given
长度 被给予具有 邀请
and the type it's beginning good file
和类型 它开始好文件
type oh there's another function
键入哦，还有另外一个功能
oh I remember why there's another helper
哦， 我记得为什么还有另一个帮手
function here that because this supports
功能在这里，因为这支持
not just text but also gifts and JPEG
不只是文字，还有礼品和JPEG
images so get file type is another
图像，以便获取文件类型是另一个
function somewhere else that telling
功能别的地方是 有说服力
which which a mime type is this
这其中，mime类型是这样的
particular file
特定文件
and and so it's putting that together
而等它放在一起
and it's an outright set out so it
它是一个彻头彻尾的阐述，因此
writes the header information out to the
写入头信息输出 到
client so it's sending back to the
客户端，以便它发送回
client and then it's going through a few
客户端，然后它会通过 几个
gyrations here to get the file open it
这里回旋获取文件打开
up and then there's a function called MF
起来，然后有一个叫 MF 功能
if you guys covered MF get yeah which is
如果你们覆盖MF得到耶这是
just a tricky way to avoid having to
只是一个取巧的办法，以避免 对
actually read the file into the machine
实际上文件读 入到本机
but basically be able to pass off a
但基本上能通断
pointer directly to or into the read it
直接指针或到阅读
through explicit read commands into yet
通过显式读取命令尚未进入
another buffer it just avoids one step
另一个缓冲区，它只是避免了一步
of buffering so all it does is map then
缓冲的所以它是所有的地图，则
of from the operating system where this
从操作系统这个地方
particular file is located and then
特定文件所在 ，然后
writes that so now it's sending it off
写道 ，所以现在它发送它关闭
to the client and so this could be done
到客户端 ，所以可以这样 做
with a regular read in a but it's a
在一个常规的读操作，但它是一个
little bit more elegant way to handle it
有点更优雅的方式来处理 它
and you'll notice by the way that the
你会 用的方式通知
content length here is the length of the
这里的内容长度的长度
file the and not does not include the
文件中 并没有不包括
number of bytes in the header so the
在报头 中 的 字节 数 ，因此
header comes first
头至上
there's no length associated with it
有没有与之相关联的长度
that so sent back but now the only way
有这么发回，但现在唯一的办法
that the client knows exactly how many
客户端 知道到底有多少
bytes that response is going to be is by
个字节， 其响应将 是 是
picking out this number in the header
挑选出这个 号码头
and reading that many bytes from we'll
从 我们 读取的字节数 会
see that in a minute but anyways this is
看到，在一分钟内 ，但不管怎么说，这是
a way of a file gets sent so now let's
文件的方式被发送所以现在让我们
just real quickly look at dynamic
只是真正的快速浏览一下动态
content so the idea of dynamic content
内容，所以动态 内容 的想法
is that lets you pass in parameters to a
就是让你在参数传递到
program that then gets executed and the
那然后被执行程序和
purpose of that
那目的
what that program then has to do is
那么，什么是程序 所要做的就是
compose a webpage and send that webpage
撰写网页和发送该网页
back to you so I'm going to demo this
回到你身边，所以我要 演示这个
with a feature built into here
具有功能内置到这里
so in particular you probably can't you
所以特别是你可能无法 你
can barely see I don't have a good way
几乎看不到我没有 一个好办法
to blow up the thing abut Dion and you
炸毁的东西 紧靠 翁和你
can also see what kind of things I look
还可以看到我是什么样的东西
at but anyways if I just say localhost
在但不管怎么说，如果我只说 本地主机
Cohen 15 to 13 that means port number 15
科恩15至13，这意味着 端口号15
to 13 on my local machine which is
13 我的本地机器上是
currently running the tiny web server
当前运行的微型Web服务器
and the only webpage available for it is
并且只 适用于它 的 网页 是
this rather stunning figure here but it
在这里，但它这个相当惊人的数字
shows that it can handle both gift
表明， 它可以 同时 处理 的礼物
content and text HTML but it also
内容和文本HTML，但它也
supports another interesting feature
支持另一个有趣的功能
which is a program that can add two
这是一个程序，可以添加两个
numbers called addcom so our idea for a
数字称为addcom所以我们 的 想法
startup coming that didn't quite make it
启动出现以后，并没有完全使它
so in particular the idea this is
所以特别的想法 ，这是
it's a CGI program it's a dynamic
这是一个CGI程序它是一个 动态
content so that I passing two numbers
内容让 我通过两个数字
embedded within the URL my request and
嵌入URL中我的请求，并
it comes back with a web page that is
它回来与 网页即
beautifully formatted like this one so
精美的格式像这样 如此
you can't see very well maybe but if you
你不能看得很清楚，也许 ， 但 如果你
look up there that teeny tiny print at
查找那里蝇头在小字
the top
顶
Yosi localhost colon 15 213 that's the
Yosi本地主机结肠癌15 213是这样的
web server and slash cgi - bin that's
Web服务器和 斜线的cgi - bin中的
what this particular server and what
这是什么特定的服务器，什么
most servers do for interpreting dynamic
大多数服务器用于解释动态做
content and then a program it's an
内容然后用一个程序它是一个
executable file called adder and then
可执行文件叫做加法，然后
the argument string that you embed in
你嵌入参数字符串
this kind of curious way the question
这种奇特的方式问题
mark and then use ampersands to separate
标记，然后用＆符号分隔
out the different fields so that's all
出了不同的 领域，使所有的
pretty standard way of handling a
处理一个非常标准的方式
dynamic content and as I said nowadays
动态内容和我说，现在
there's a lot fancier ways of doing it
有做了很多发烧友的方式
but that's sort of the basic way and
但这 是排序的基本方式
you'll see it still
你还是会看到它
going to use today so imagine that this
今天要去用这么想象，这
time it's a get request but instead of
一次，它是一个GET请求，但不是
the adder function at some other Perl
在一些其他的Perl加法器功能
program that is sitting on the server
程序是坐在服务器上
somewhere called Eng and we won't worry
地方叫工程，我们也不会担心
about what that program does we'll just
有关程序做什么我们就
show you the idea behind it so in
告诉你它背后的想法所以在
particularly there's a get request comes
特别是有一个GET请求是
in and it says cgi-bin
在和它说的cgi-bin
and then the next argument is
再下一个参数是
interpreted as the name of a file and
解释为一个文件 的名称 和
what will happen then is that the server
那么，什么会发生的是，服务器
will spawn off a process
将产生断过程
using our friends fork and exec which
使用我们的朋友fork和exec这
you know so well now during the shell
外壳期间，您现在知道这么好
lab so and that that program will
实验室了，那 该程序会
execute will execute and it will its job
执行会执行 ，它会自己的工作
then is to generate a file in HTML of
然后就是生成的HTML文件
format and then the server will send the
格式，然后服务器会发送
result back to the client
结果返回给客户端
so there's a few details we got to
所以有我们得到了几个细节
figure out to make this work
弄清楚，使这项工作
one is how will I actually pass
一个是我怎么会真正通过
arguments how will end PL know what's
争论如何收场PL知道什么是
being passed to it as arguments how ng
被传递给它的参数如何NG
I'll get whatever page HTML it creates
我会得到任何网页的HTML它创建
back to the server so that the server
返回到服务器，使服务器
can send it to the client those are all
可以 将它发送给 客户端这些都是
the sort of details of the CGI
排序的CGI的细节
specification CGI stands for common
规范CGI代表通用
gateway interface
网关接口
so you just saw a demo of edcom and so
所以你刚才看到的演示edcom 等
let's just look at how this works so as
让我们看一看 如何工作的 ，从而
I mentioned the way things get passed is
我 提到的事情获得通过的方式是
within the URL you include the program
在URL中包含你的程序
name and then the question mark is what
命名并问号是什么
is like the Terminator for the program
就像终结者的程序
name and then all the other arguments
名字，然后所有的其他参数
with ampersands between them and you
他们和你之间的 ＆符号
can't have any blanks in here so they
不能有任何空白的，因此他们
put present 20s and as you probably see
把目前20多岁，你可能会看到
in various other those are called escape
在各种其他那些被称为 逃逸
codes when you can't use a particular
代码时，你可以不使用特定的
character how do you encode it in some
性格你怎么对其进行编码， 在一些
other way
另一种方式
you
您
so the first thing is how does the
所以第一件事情是怎么做的
server then pass the argument to the
服务器然后传递参数给
program that gets executed well it's
这被执行程序以及它的
really weird the way it does it is by
很奇怪它的方式是通过
creating an environment variable for
创造 一个 环境变量
your machine
你的机器
that's called query string and so the
这就是所谓的查询字符串等等
server defines that environment variable
服务器定义环境变量
and then the job on the CGI side of the
再上的CGI的出侧的作业
script is to then retrieve that
脚本是再检索
environment variable is a way of getting
环境变量是 获取 的 一种方式
the string you can already see hey wait
你已经可以看到字符串等一下
a minute what if you were running
一分钟你正在运行什么，如果
multiple servers at once you can see
同时你可以 看到多台服务器
you've got a problem here but actually
你在这里，但实际上有一个问题
no environments are specific to
没有环境所特有的
particular processes so this will work
特别流程，使这将工作
so it's creating for the application
所以它为应用程序创建
program that we'll be able to sort of
的程序， 我们就 可以进行排序
retrieve from the operating system
从操作系统检索
essentially what arguments were passed
本质上是通过什么样的参数
to the are being passed to it
在被传递给它
and so this is what the code looks like
所以这是代码的样子
for the dynamic server again it's going
再次动态服务器这是怎么回事
to write back some information back to
回写一些信息反馈给
the the client and let's look at this
在客户端，让我们来看看 这个
and now it's going to set up this CGI
现在它要建立这个 CGI
query string environment variable and
查询字符串环境变量
then use our friends dupe and exec
然后使用我们的朋友欺骗和exec
basically to redirect the standard
基本上重定向标准
output to its client oh I'm sorry
输出给它的客户哦对不起
the file descriptor is the the client
文件描述符是客户端
file descriptor so it will tell it's
文件描述符所以它会告诉它的
going to go and we're in a fork I'm
要去，我们正处在一个叉，我
sorry so now we're in the child process
抱歉，所以现在我们在子 进程
okay let me read all the code and within
好让我读所有的代码和内
the child process it's going to rename
子进程这将 重新命名
the it's standard output so that it's
在它的标准输出 ，以便它的
writing directly to the client and and
直接写入 到客户端，并
then call exec which as you know it's
然后调用exec正如你 知道这是
the way you take this program which is
你的方式采取这种方案，这是
just given by a file name and fire it up
只是一个 文件名给出火起来
and get it going with that defined
并把它 与定义 去
environment value and then this is the
环境值，那么这是
parent we'll just wait until the child
父我们就等到 孩子
complete
完成
okay so now we're almost done
好吧，现在我们几乎已经完成
so the now this is what the actual
所以，现在这是实际
program the adder program does the one
编程加法器程序将一个
that the CGI program the one that's been
该CGI程序的一个一直
forked off and exempt so it creates then
分叉断及豁免因此它创建再
the HTML that you want to send back and
要 发回的HTML 和
here it's pretty mundane the only actual
这是很平常的唯一实际
HTML and here are the PS meeting
HTML和这里的 PS会议
paragraphs Merkers so this is literally
段Merkers所以这是字面上
generating HTTP HTML content and storing
生成HTTP的HTML内容，并存储
them all in a string called content and
他们都在一个字符串称为内容和
now it wants to send that content back
现在它希望这些内容发送回
and you saw before that the server
在你面前， 服务器看到
already filled in the top-level stuff
已经填写顶层 的东西
but I have to tell what is the type and
但我要告诉 是什么类型，
how many bytes is is so I'll use sterlin
多少字节是如此，我将使用sterlin
to figure out how many bytes I'm sending
要弄清楚我多少字节发送
back and the content type and then I
背部和内容类型，然后我
will and I'm pretty effing this which as
将我敢这样艾芬作为其
you recall ivory mapped a standard
你还记得象牙映射标准
output now is talking directly to the
输出现在是直接 谈话 的
client and just to be sure it all goes
客户端和公正，以确保一切顺利
out I'll flush that out of there and so
出来我就冲 了 这 一点的存在，因此
what's happening here then is that it's
这里发生了什么，然后是它的
the job of the CGI program to write the
CGI程序的工作写
HTML and to send it back to the the
HTML 并把它发回 的
client
客户
so again let's just do a real quick demo
如此反复，让我们只是做一个真正的快速演示
here got just enough time
这里仅获得足够的时间
Oh
哦
so I've got the tiny web server running
所以我已经得到了非常微小的Web服务器上运行
down at the bottom and I'm using telnet
倒在底部 ，我使用telnet
to reach it and so now I want to say
到达它，所以现在 我想说
I have to take time / CGI - Ben / adder
我必须花时间/ CGI - 奔 /加法
what numbers you want to add 17 and 13
要添加17和13 号是什么
you don't get many shots at it so I like
你没有得到 它 很多的镜头 ，所以我喜欢
to double check I'm doing
仔细 检查 我做的
we worked always mixed so it shouldn't
我们的工作总是褒贬不一，因此不应该
surprise you what comes back because you
令你感到惊讶什么回来，因为你
just saw that Cosette did it but what
刚才看到珂赛特做到了，但什么
you see then is that this first three
你看到的则是，这前三
line got generated by the the server
得到了由服务器生成线
code that comes back with the okay
与奥凯回来代码
information about the server and then
关于服务器，然后信息
the content length was generated by the
通过将所生成的内容的长度
CGI program adder and the content type
CGI程序和 加法器 的内容类型
and then this is the HTML that you saw
然后这是 你 看到 的 HTML
being generated so it's actually what
正在生成所以它实际上是什么
people say about this early world wide
人们说这个早全世界
web and it's gotten a lot more
网络和 它得到了很多
complicated is the best thing Tim
复杂的是最好的东西添
berners-lee was to figure out how simple
伯纳斯-李是弄清楚如何简单
it could be because other people were
这可能是因为其他人都
working much more exotic ways to get
工作更加奇特的方式来获得
different agents to talk to each other
不同的 代理商相互交谈
over the Internet
通过互联网
and what berners-lee figured out is we
和伯纳斯 - 李想通了什么就是我们
can just kind of cobble together
可以只是一种凑齐
standard ideas of sockets interface have
套接字接口的标准的想法有
some protocol pretty straightforward
一些协议非常 简单
protocol handle different content type
协议处理不同的内容类型
set up these dynamic things by forking
通过派生建立这些动态的东西
off a process every time which is
关每 这 时的处理
extraordinarily inefficient way to do it
非常低效的方式做到这一点
like to add two numbers by forking off a
想通过派生关闭添加两个数字的
whole process and doing it is totally
整个过程，这样做是完全
absurd but then shows add calm but you
荒诞却又那么说明添加平静，但是 你
know it's not it's in some ways that he
知道这是不是它在某些方面，他
took a bunch of ideas that existed and
拿了一堆的想法 存在，
figured out how to put it together and
想出如何把它放在一起，
I'll recognize that the value people
我认识到价值的人
would obtain from that and it took the
会从获取和它采取了
internet from being something that was
被东西是互联网
certainly used by nerdy people to talk
当然使用书呆子人交谈
to each other and opened it up to all
对方并打开了它所有的
the things that we know of today so it
我们知道 今天 的 所以它的东西
was a huge step forward I give them full
是一个巨大的进步，我给他们充分的
credit even if from a technical point of
信贷即使从技术角度
view it's actually fairly
查看它 实际上 是 相当
straightforward okay so that will do us
简单好了，所以， 会做我们
through today
通过今天